<?xml-stylesheet href="/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dhruv Adha</title>
    <link>https://dhruv34.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dhruv Adha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 16:58:26 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://dhruv34.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Reading In Education</title>
        <link>https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/readinginedu/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 16:58:26 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/readinginedu/</guid>
        <description>Dhruv Adha https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/readinginedu/ -&lt;p&gt;Most people go through a book phase in middle school but drop it sometime in early high school when books become assignments rather than fun. Instead of lenses into new worlds, books become a waste of time, a hassle preventing us from what we really want to do. I went from reading 3-4 hours per day in middle school to, within a year, replacing high school reading assignments with Sparknotes binges before class. Not all of these were “boring” books either—I would&amp;rsquo;ve loved The Kite Runner had I read it willingly. I’ve heard the same story that I experienced from so many friends. I was lucky enough in college to have a few weeks of motivation and some great books to get back into reading as a hobby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe the problem is that we teach reading in the same way that we teach math and science. It is treated as a formulaic task of memorization rather than a creative journey. The moment when we are taught to annotate books for a certain theme or literary device is the moment when the fun and imagination dissipates from the book for most people. I remember dashing through great books such as To Kill a Mockingbird scanning for similes, motifs, and characterization to highlight instead of actually enjoying the material and stepping into Harper Lee’s 1930s with the Finches. While it may be true that teenagers refuse everything forced upon them, the education system rewards memorization and knowledge rather than genuine interest and love for the craft. It is understandable that students are forced to learn biology and calculus, but drilling into students the art of writing a 5 page essay on the significance of personification in a book is self-defeating. Almost everyone I know has come out of high school English class with worse reading habits than going in. After basic literacy, reading should be encouraged as a playground where students can explore and formulate their own thoughts and opinions. It should be an art like painting or orchestra, not a ‘hard subject’ like calculus.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/readinginedu/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>A Man Called Ove</title>
        <link>https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/amancalledove/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 16:58:26 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/amancalledove/</guid>
        <description>Dhruv Adha https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/amancalledove/ -- https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/amancalledove/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>About Me</title>
        <link>https://dhruv34.github.io/posts/aboutme/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 16:58:26 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://dhruv34.github.io/posts/aboutme/</guid>
        <description>Dhruv Adha https://dhruv34.github.io/posts/aboutme/ -&lt;p&gt;Hello! My name is Dhruv Adha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently graduated from Georgia Tech with a bachelors in Computer Science specializing in Artificial Intelligence and Modeling/Simulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to high school in Scottsdale, Arizona but now live in Dublin, OH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my free time, I enjoy reading, working on projects, and watching and playing soccer!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/dhruv-adha-ba5142215/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/-LinkedIn-blue?style=flat-square&amp;amp;logo=linkedin&amp;amp;logoColor=white&#34; alt=&#34;LinkedIn&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dhruv34&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/-GitHub-black?style=flat-square&amp;amp;logo=github&amp;amp;logoColor=white&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dhruv34.github.io/resume.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/-Resume-darkgreen?style=flat-square&amp;amp;logo=adobeacrobatreader&amp;amp;logoColor=white&#34; alt=&#34;Resume&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:dhruv0515@gmail.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/-Email-red?style=flat-square&amp;amp;logo=gmail&amp;amp;logoColor=white&#34; alt=&#34;Email&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://dhruv34.github.io/posts/aboutme/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Beartown</title>
        <link>https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/beartown/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 16:58:26 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/beartown/</guid>
        <description>Dhruv Adha https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/beartown/ -&lt;p&gt;Probably my go-to recommendation to friends. Backman carves out every character so brilliantly that you end up connecting with each one, even in their worst times. Set in a declining small hockey town in the middle of nowhere, we experience a community stumbling through hard times and yet see depictions of genuine connection. Backman has a brand of magical realism where every character feels real and everything feels like it will work out in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you are honest, people may deceive you. Be honest anyway. If you are kind, people may accuse you of selfishness. Be kind anyway. All the good you do today will be forgotten by others tomorrow. Do good anyway. What you create, others can destroy. Create anyway. Because in the end, it is between you and God. It was never between you and anyone else anyway.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;All adults have days when we feel completely drained. When we no longer know quite what we spend so much time fighting for, when reality and everyday worries overwhelm us and we wonder how much longer we’re going to be able to carry on. The wonderful thing is that we can all live through far more days like that without breaking than we think. The terrible thing is that we never know exactly how many.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The simple truth, repeated as often as it is ignored, is that if you tell a child it can do absolutely anything, or that it can’t do anything at all, you will in all likelihood be proven right.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Being a parent makes you feel like a blanket that’s always too small. No matter how hard you try to cover everyone, there’s always someone who’s freezing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;He never loses control, never gets excited, because you just don’t if you’re always living in the future.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We devote ourselves to sports because they remind us of how small we are just as much as they make us bigger.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;People sometimes say that sorrow is mental but longing is physical. One is a wound, the other an amputated limb, a withered petal compared to a snapped stem. Anything that grows closely enough to what it loves will eventually share the same roots. We can talk about loss, we can treat it and give it time, but biology still forces us to live according to certain rules: plants that are split down the middle don’t heal, they die.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hockey is just a silly little game. We devote year after year after year to it without ever really hoping to get anything in return. We burn and bleed and cry, fully aware that the most the sport can give us, in the very best scenario, is incomprehensibly meager and worthless: just a few isolated moments of transcendence. That’s all. But what the hell else is life made of?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Everyone has a thousand wishes before a tragedy, but just one afterward.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The easiest way to unite a group isn’t through love, because love is hard. It makes demands. Hate is simple.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/beartown/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Books and Content Consumption</title>
        <link>https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/booksandcontent/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 16:58:26 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/booksandcontent/</guid>
        <description>Dhruv Adha https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/booksandcontent/ -&lt;p&gt;In today’s increasingly materialistic world filled with a hyper-fixation on fast money, constant success, and an existential need for productivity, reading often feels like a waste of time. Especially as an ambitious person in my early 20’s, I question why I spend so many hours in imaginary worlds reading about make-believe people. Maybe I should be learning a new skill or figuring out how to make more money. With sources of instant dopamine all around us, it is even easier to fill empty hours with doom scrolling on your choice of short-form content which has infected every platform: TikTok, Instagram, Youtube, even LinkedIn. And that is what I often end up doing, only to regret it after the 30 minute trance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hobbies let us take our minds off of whatever is going on in our lives. While social media scratches the itch, reading makes me feel much better after. A novel offers a much longer story that actually requires a significant time investment from the consumer, automatically creating a deeper connection than we can ever have with a TikTok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some ask why people choose to read books when they can just watch movies or shows. I believe there is value in imagination and creating characters and worlds in our heads rather than being force-fed a rendering of a story by some well-paid team of directors. A character can look however a reader wants; we never criticize or question fragments outside of the story such as how well an actor fits a role. The magic of reading happens, paradoxically, when we stop reading. Something shocking, sad, or exciting happens and we pause, thinking about our own lives. The control of pacing really does matter; when watching a film, we just sit back and give away control of the best part of a story to actors and directors - imagination. By taking a more active role in consuming content, we can learn so much more through a great novel than any movie could teach us.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/booksandcontent/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Deep Learning Streetview Geolocation</title>
        <link>https://dhruv34.github.io/projects/geo/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 16:58:26 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://dhruv34.github.io/projects/geo/</guid>
        <description>Dhruv Adha https://dhruv34.github.io/projects/geo/ -&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Constructed a Street View images dataset of major cities using online datasets and the Google Maps API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used the CLIP zero-shot model as a baseline and tested it for different label parameters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Constructed and fine-tuned ResNet, DenseNet, and CNN models, achieving a 81% test accuracy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dhruv34/geolocationDL&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/-GitHub-black?style=flat-square&amp;amp;logo=github&amp;amp;logoColor=white&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dhruv34.github.io/geo.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/-Report-blue?style=flat-square&amp;amp;logo=microsoftword&amp;amp;logoColor=white&#34; alt=&#34;Report&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dhruv34.github.io/geoPoster.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/-Poster-teal?style=flat-square&amp;amp;logo=image&amp;amp;logoColor=white&#34; alt=&#34;Poster&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://dhruv34.github.io/projects/geo/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Fiction vs Nonfiction</title>
        <link>https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/fictionnonfiction/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 16:58:26 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/fictionnonfiction/</guid>
        <description>Dhruv Adha https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/fictionnonfiction/ -&lt;p&gt;There are different types of readers who read for different reasons. In my experience, there are two major groups: those who read to understand the world and those who read to escape it. I tend to fall into the first category. I enjoy slow, character-driven books about regular people more than action-filled high fantasy novels. But if I want to learn more about the world, why don’t I read nonfiction, specifically self-help? After all, self-help books get right to the point. I’ve asked myself that many times and pick up a self-help book at least once every couple months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I never truly enjoy them as much as I enjoy fiction. I’ve read books that explain how to improve in an area I struggle with which should be a manual for my life. While they are useful to think about while I read them, they never stick with me or give me motivation for real change. They just feel like another motivational YouTube video. Meanwhile, my favorite fiction books have stuck with me whenever I am making a decision. The reason is simple: the best teacher is experience, not a lecture. People often repeat the cliche that failures are necessary for progress. When we can’t use our experience as a lesson, the second best thing is someone else’s experience. Fiction provides exactly that. Most of all, I love reading about people who go through similar problems as I do and grow as people. Meanwhile, self-help is crammed with life lessons which really do take a lifetime to learn. Without the context and experience behind a piece of advice, they feel like empty platitudes. More like slogans rather than lessons. That’s also why the best self-help books are just stories of the author’s life. Fiction is amazing because the best stories transport a reader into a new world and transmit lessons through characters that feel real.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/fictionnonfiction/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>SubjECTive-QA</title>
        <link>https://dhruv34.github.io/projects/subjective/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 16:58:26 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://dhruv34.github.io/projects/subjective/</guid>
        <description>Dhruv Adha https://dhruv34.github.io/projects/subjective/ -&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Published paper to NeurIPS and presented findings at the SouthNLP 2024 Symposium.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Constructed SubjECTive-QA: a novel dataset of earnings call transcripts for training LLMs in financial analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trained NLP models such as BERT, FinBERT, and RoBERTa using our custom database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gtfintechlab/SubjECTive-QA&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/-GitHub-black?style=flat-square&amp;amp;logo=github&amp;amp;logoColor=white&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.20651&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/-Publication-darkblue?style=flat-square&amp;amp;logo=openaccess&amp;amp;logoColor=white&#34; alt=&#34;Publication&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://neurips.cc/virtual/2024/poster/97586&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/-Poster-teal?style=flat-square&amp;amp;logo=image&amp;amp;logoColor=white&#34; alt=&#34;Poster&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cc.gatech.edu/news/new-dataset-takes-aim-subjective-misinformation-earnings-calls-and-other-public-hearings&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/-Article-orange?style=flat-square&amp;amp;logo=medium&amp;amp;logoColor=white&#34; alt=&#34;Article&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://dhruv34.github.io/projects/subjective/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Goldman Sachs | Summer Analyst</title>
        <link>https://dhruv34.github.io/experience/goldman/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 16:58:26 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://dhruv34.github.io/experience/goldman/</guid>
        <description>Dhruv Adha https://dhruv34.github.io/experience/goldman/ -&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python, Javascript, React.js, ANTLR4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automated the applied margin calculation process for syndicated loans within Investment Banking Engineering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed a domain specific language with ANTLR4 for parsing and communicating 100+ credit agreements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed an end-to-end application for the GS Digital Loan Agent using TypeScript, React, and Next.js.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Led collaboration with the Investment Banking Operations team to design the loans pricing grid with Figma.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My intern project was to reinvent the existing pricing grid for syndicated loans. The pricing grid tells agents how the interest rate changes as certain key performance indicators (KPIs) are hit by the borrower. The existing pricing grid was depicted as an n-dimenstional matrix for n KPIs. As a result, for more complex credit agreements, the pricing grid would become too complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first two weeks, I worked with my manager a loans agent to develop a rule-based representation of the pricing grid. Then, we used ANTLR4 to create a domain specific language to communicate the rules between systems. With the DSL in place, my task for the remaining of the summer was to create a read-only dashboard expressing the rules and another editable dashboard allowing agents to change the terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The read-only mode was fairly simple and I completed it in 2 weeks. However, the edit-mode took the remaining of the summer. Front-end programming was new to me so I had to spend time outside of work learning Javascript, ReactJS, and Goldman Sachs&amp;rsquo;s internal UI Toolkit. These tools had to combined with our Python backend to create a complete product. I worked with agents and UX developers to create Figma mock-ups of the dashboards. The major challenge was that each time I had reached a near-finished product, we would come up with new requirements and edge cases. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until the second-to-last day of the internship that I made my last PR to fix the dashboard. Although I know that the pricing grid will require new changes and evolve over time, I was happy to see my progress through the internship and really enjoyed my experience!&lt;/p&gt;
- https://dhruv34.github.io/experience/goldman/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>John Deere | MLOps Engineer</title>
        <link>https://dhruv34.github.io/experience/johndeere/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 16:58:26 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://dhruv34.github.io/experience/johndeere/</guid>
        <description>Dhruv Adha https://dhruv34.github.io/experience/johndeere/ -&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Java, Python, AWS, APIs, SQL, Databricks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built a scalable data pipeline architecture leveraging AWS CloudFormation, SNS queues, and S3 buckets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed REST APIs to provide analytics insights for data science teams using Java and Python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced customer request management using Databricks and distributed computing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Led testing efforts for MLOps products, creating and executing 200+ unit tests with Pytest-mock.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most of my junior year, I took a reduced courseload and decided to get some more industry experience before graduating. So, I worked as a part-time engineer in the MLOps team at John Deere, working 10-15 hours per week alongside classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first two months of my time was spent working on the CI/CD pipeline of the MLOps team I was placed in. I learned how to use GitHub Workflows and created checks on pull requests before allowing developers to push their code such as checking unit test coverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then stepped in to work alongside team members on multiple tasks. This included a data science project using Databricks for distributed computing and building and testing APIs with Postman and Swagger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the final 2 months, I worked on a larger project: creating an AWS architecture for data science teams to easily engage with a large database. The problem was that developers didn&amp;rsquo;t know when data was updated so they had to repeatedly pull the database whenever they began working. This process would take 30 to 40 minutes and would drain valuable time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address this, I used AWS CloudFormation to create a system that notifies developers when data was updated. Specifically, I used an API to poll the data source ever so often and when it detects a change, it would send information about that change to a SNS Queue. I then added data science teams&amp;rsquo; Microsoft Teams chats as subscribers to the SNS queue so they receive messages when data is updated. I also used EC2 Instances to process and transform the incoming data changes for efficient consumption and S3 buckets to store data about past updates.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://dhruv34.github.io/experience/johndeere/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss> 