<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bookrecs on Dhruv Adha</title>
    <link>https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bookrecs on Dhruv Adha</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 16:58:26 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reading In Education</title>
      <link>https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/readinginedu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 16:58:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/readinginedu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most people go through a book phase in middle school but drop it sometime in early high school when books become assignments rather than fun. Instead of lenses into new worlds, books become a waste of time, a hassle preventing us from what we really want to do. I went from reading 3-4 hours per day in middle school to, within a year, replacing high school reading assignments with Sparknotes binges before class. Not all of these were “boring” books either—I would&amp;rsquo;ve loved The Kite Runner had I read it willingly. I’ve heard the same story that I experienced from so many friends. I was lucky enough in college to have a few weeks of motivation and some great books to get back into reading as a hobby.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Man Called Ove</title>
      <link>https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/amancalledove/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 16:58:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/amancalledove/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beartown</title>
      <link>https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/beartown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 16:58:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/beartown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Probably my go-to recommendation to friends. Backman carves out every character so brilliantly that you end up connecting with each one, even in their worst times. Set in a declining small hockey town in the middle of nowhere, we experience a community stumbling through hard times and yet see depictions of genuine connection. Backman has a brand of magical realism where every character feels real and everything feels like it will work out in the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Books and Content Consumption</title>
      <link>https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/booksandcontent/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 16:58:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/booksandcontent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s increasingly materialistic world filled with a hyper-fixation on fast money, constant success, and an existential need for productivity, reading often feels like a waste of time. Especially as an ambitious person in my early 20’s, I question why I spend so many hours in imaginary worlds reading about make-believe people. Maybe I should be learning a new skill or figuring out how to make more money. With sources of instant dopamine all around us, it is even easier to fill empty hours with doom scrolling on your choice of short-form content which has infected every platform: TikTok, Instagram, Youtube, even LinkedIn. And that is what I often end up doing, only to regret it after the 30 minute trance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fiction vs Nonfiction</title>
      <link>https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/fictionnonfiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 16:58:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dhruv34.github.io/bookrecs/fictionnonfiction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are different types of readers who read for different reasons. In my experience, there are two major groups: those who read to understand the world and those who read to escape it. I tend to fall into the first category. I enjoy slow, character-driven books about regular people more than action-filled high fantasy novels. But if I want to learn more about the world, why don’t I read nonfiction, specifically self-help? After all, self-help books get right to the point. I’ve asked myself that many times and pick up a self-help book at least once every couple months.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
